www.linkedin.com/in/isabellepeyrichoux

isabelle_peyrichoux@yahoo.ca

Isabelle Peyrichoux

Mountain View, California 415-624-6335

Objective: Co-Active Coach

With 10 years of experience in the Internet industry as a user experience researcher, I am on the path to becoming a full time co-active coach. I have a talent and passion for helping people discover and fulfill their greatest potential, passions, and dreams. I am bringing a multifaceted professional and personal experience in life coaching, counselling, psychology, and personality theories to my coaching practice. Exceptional listening skills, very respectful and non-judgmental attitude, well versed presentation and facilitation skills with exceptional feedback.

International experience: US, Canada, France, UK, and Switzerland. Bilingual English-French. Dual citizenship: French and Canadian.

- Co-active coaching
- Workshop facilitation
- Motivational presentations
- Writing:articles
- Project management, need assesment, and consultative approach
- Myers-Briggs Certification
- Personality Theories (Temperaments, Interaction Styles and Cognitive Processes)
- Humanistic Psychology, Counseling and Personal Development theories and practices (including creativity, emotional intelligence, self-actualization)

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Individual Coaching and Interviews

- Designed and conducted one-on-one coaching sessions to define needs, values and talents, and foster personal development and improved communications, using Temperament, Interaction Styles and Personality Types (Keirsey, Berens, MBTI). Resulted in higher appreciation of self and others, and improved relationships.
- Conducted 60+ counseling sessions with clients and students. Recognized for my exceptional listening skills and, very respectful and non-judgmental attitude.
- Designed, planned and facilitated 600+ individual or group interviews, in the US, Canada, France, and Africa, resulting in deep insights which led to user experience and product innovation. Co-inventor of three filed patents.
- Wrote articles in professional magazines about applying counseling techniques and empathy to user research and interviewing techniques. Articles very well received and referenced by practitioners and academics internationally.

Workshop Design and Facilitation

- Yahoo! Designed and facilitated workshops to foster productive work relationships using models of individual differences (Temperament, Interaction Styles and Personality Types). Excellent ratings and feedback.
 Workshop led to higher understanding and appreciation of co-workers and insights to better interact with them.
- Delivered 100+ presentations about user insights to influence user interface and product innovation, to both small & large audiences (5-80), from various functions (Marketing, Engineering, Product Managers, and Scientists) at all levels in the organization. Additionally, delivered presentations to Professional Organizations.
- Delivered inspirational talks on achieving personal goals through mountain climbing. Strong motivational impact on attendees.

Project Management and Consultative Approach

- Managed 60+ projects in the US, Canada, UK, France and internationally (2-30 countries and 2-5 continents), in English and French, on-site and remotely, ranging from 1 week to 2 years.
- Collaborated with up to 40 internal and external stakeholders, at all levels in the organization, in cross-cultural, and cross-functional teams (Engineering, Product Managers, Scientists, Marketing, Human Resources, and Finances) to advocate user needs and help design innovative, useful and easy to use interfaces.
- Consistently delivered high-quality, on-time results through exceptional listening and interviewing skills, thorough understanding of needs, empathy and adaptation to stakeholders' constraints, diplomacy, understanding of interpersonal dynamics, and rigorous follow-through and planning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YAHOO!, Sunnyvale, California

Oct 2007 - Dec 2010

Senior Researcher, Search Customer Insights

Planned and conducted user research to influence Yahoo! Search product strategy and design, working in cross-functional teams.

BELL WEB SOLUTIONS, Montreal, Canada

2004 - 2007

Senior Consultant, User Experience Research and Design

Consulted with large companies to plan and conduct the most appropriate methodology for user research. Also, designed site interaction easy to use and meeting user needs.

THE FRENCH SPEAKING UNIVERSITY AGENCY, Montreal, Canada

2001 - 2004

Project Manager, User Experience Researcher and Interaction Designer

Led international Internet and intranet projects for up to 2000 users worldwide (employees, scientists). Designed site interaction.

ABC PUBLISHERS, Birmingham, United Kingdom

2001

Information Architect & Webmaster

THE FRENCH ATOMIC COMMISSION, Paris Area, France

2000

User Experience Researcher and Architect

EDUCATION

Associate Degree, Psychology, Foothill College (expected graduation: August 2012)

Two-year Certificate, Counseling and Psychotherapy, Montreal Counseling Center, Montreal, Canada Master's Degree, Information Science, Institute for Engineering Studies, Paris, France Master's Degree, Archaeology and Art History, Toulouse-Le Mirail University, Toulouse, France

PROFESSIONAL AND PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT

- MBTI and Interstrength Certification Program, Interstrength Associates, Huntington Beach, CA
- Coached by an expert coach in the design and moderation of Personality Types Workshops
- 50+ seminars on the theory, training and coaching of Personality Theories
- 10+ courses on presentation, communication, brainstorm moderation, and interviewing techniques
- 150+ books on Personal development, psychology and personality theories.
- **15+ years of personal growth** through seminars, books, counseling and introspection. Focus: self-actualization, improving relationships, career development, reaching professional and personal goals
- Micro-blogging about personal development to inspire others grow and realize their potential

AFFILIATIONS/MEMBERSHIPS

Association for Psychological Type International (APTi) Bay Area Association of Psychological Type (BAAPT)